Preliminary Guide to the Grosvenor Chapman papers, 1931-1994 MS2181
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Publicity, 1957-1993; Series 8
  - Press Waterfront, 1978; Series 8 (Box 24, Folder Folder 8)
  - Press Waterfront, 1977; Series 8 (Box 24, Folder Folder 9)
  - Press: Waterfront, 1965-1971; Series 8 (Box 43, Folder Folder 1)
  - Program: 11th Washington D.C. home and furniture show, 1957 February; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder Folder 18)
  - Promotional material C.A.G. by S.C.O.W. [Citizens Association of Georgetown, Sailing Club of Washington], 1973-1978; Series 8 (Box 25, Folder Folder 6)
  - Propaganda C.A.G. [Citizens Association of Georgetown], 1972-1976; Series 8 (Box 25, Folder Folder 3)
  - Publicity press publications, 1945-1953; Series 8 (Box 11, Folder Folder 8)
  - Publicity S.C.O.W [Sailing Club of Washington], 1975; Series 8 (Box 25, Folder Folder 5)
  - The Reporter, 1967 January 26; Series 8 (Box 42, Folder Folder 23)
  - The Scientific American, 1965 September; Series 8 (Box 42, Folder Folder 24)
  - Washington Post clippings, 1985; Series 8 (Box 13, Folder Folder 3)
  - Whitehurst Freeway press, 1984; Series 8 (Box 34, Folder Folder 1)
- Architectural work of Grosvenor Chapman, 1939-1988; Series 10; 3 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains slides, architectural drawings, topographical maps, and newspaper articles. These records date from 1939-1988 with the bulk in the 1950s and 1960s.
  - Photographs, 1950-1963; Series 10 (Box 45)
    This box contains photographs of the interior and exterior of homes designed by Grosvenor Chapman. Some of these images have handwritten notes attached with details about what is in the images.
  - Architectural articles, 1946-1953; Series 10 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Architectural drawings and topgraphical maps, 1954-1988; Series 10 (Box 46)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1956; Series 10 (Box 47)
    Contains newspaper articles, photographs, and architectural drawings.
  - The Georgetowner newspaper (various issues), 1965-1972; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - The Georgetowner newspaper (various issues), 1972-1973; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - The Georgetowner newspaper (various issues), 1973-1977; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - The Georgetown Spectator newspaper (various issues), 1967, 1971; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper articles, undated; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper articles, undated; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper articles, undated; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper articles, undated; Series 10 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Images of houses [slides], undated; Series 10 (Box 49)
    Subjects include (slide holder 1) NAHB lecture, St. Thomas pictures, Powel Model, Parents Magazine house, Eastgate Model, NIH, Children's Village; (slide holder 2) Marshall house, 3335 Q, 1517 34th, Cohen house, Thad Brown house, Bending Lane develop, Murray house, Semmes house, Seiler house Robinson house, Freeman alter, and Sullivan
  - Images of Georgetown and Adams Fosters house [slides], 1977, undated; Series 10 (Box 50, Carton 1)
    Note on box says "duplicates and unsuitable"
  - GPC status of development [slides], 1965; Series 10 (Box 50, Carton 2)
    Please note the outside of the original storage box reads Georgetown Planning Council.
  - GPG Whitehurst [Geogetown Planning Council] [slides], 1965; Series 10 (Box 50, Carton 3)
    Please note the written note reads either GPC or GPg, but the outside of the original box says "Geo. Planning Council"
  - GPC Plans [slides], 1965; Series 10 (Box 50, Carton 4)
    Please note: the written descriptive note reads GPG or GPc, but the original carton reads Geo. Planning Council.
  - GPC Sketches [slides], 1965; Series 10 (Box 50, Carton 5)
  - Potomac Scenes [slides], 1978; Series 10 (Box 50, Carton 6)
- Recordings, undated; Series 11; 1 Linear Feet
  This series contains audio cassettes. All the data known about each cassette is listed in a general note for that cassette.
  Arrangement
  These recordings may also fit subject wise in other series, but because of the lack of information known about the recordings they were retained in a separated series.
  - Sen. Hatfield hearing, undated; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 1)
    Senator Hatfield hearing Whalen, David Childs, Carter Brown, Herb Miller
  - Sen. Hatfield hearing, 1973 August 6; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 2)
    Written on cassette: Mike Frome, et al.; Poor & Sullivan; Everett Scott
  - NCPC, 1973 August 6; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 3)
    Written on the cassette: Wallace, Economics, Banks
  - C & O Canal [Chesapeake and Ohio Canal], undated; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 4)
    Written on the cassette: Wesley, [C.S] A. Fisher, [unintelligible word that may be Wove or Movie?]
  - Develop, undated; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 5)
    Illegible writing on cassette may read: groude, gam abbott
  - Pratt, undated; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 6)
    Illegible writing on cassette
  - Cassette, undated; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 7)
    Illegible writing on cassette include initial KW, DS, FM, GC
  - Nat. Trust, 1973 August; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 8)
    Illegible writing on cassette include William Dugas, et al,
  - Cassette, undated; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 9)
  - Georgetown Waterfront Decision, 1975; Series 11 (Box 50, Cassette 10)
    Written on cassette: WETA 1975 Upchurch and Chapman, Tom Lipman, Wash. Post moderator